Did I just die?
Elsa... What was that woman
doing in the mansion?
This is... the graveyard?
So... right after the trial?
Or—
Emilia!
Subaru?
Yeah, that's right. It's me.
It wasn't me! It wasn't!
I know.
It's okay. Everything's okay.
Subaru...
I'm sorry.
I've finally calmed down.
Emilia...
Are you feeling all right?
Yes... because Subaru was
there for me, I think.
We need to talk about the trial now.
Yeah... but I have a pretty
good idea of what it's about.
It showed you your past, right?
Past?
How the hell do you know
what happens in the trial?
You saw the ruins glowing, didn't you?
I was qualified to do it, too.
And...
I passed it.
Hmm... Young Su passed, eh?
Assuming he's not joking,
that's quite an achievement.
If it's true, we can remove the barrier.
Garf, how does the barrier look now?
No changes.
So you lied. Drop dead.
You reached that conclusion too fast!
What's wrong, Garfiel?
Not a damn thing's wrong.
Subaru...
If that's true, how...
What did you see?
I wouldn't say I "saw"...
More like I "realized."
It seems like there's not just
one of these sadistic trials.
There are three in total, apparently.
So... two more?
Emilia, I have a suggestion.
You might not like it, though.
A suggestion?
I could do the remaining trials in your place,
and pass them. That's my suggestion.
I want to be your strength.
I don't know what you saw in your past,
but if it made you cry so hard and
look like you were in such pain...
I want to lend you a hand.
Hang on!
You've just been sayin' whatever the
hell you want while we sit and listen,
but I don't want anyone but the princess,
Emilia-sama, bein' the one
to go through the trial.
At the very least, you're the last person
I wanna see gettin' rid of the barrier!
You can go through the trial
in Emilia-sama's place.
Wait, wait, wait!
What? You're surprised that I'm against it?
You're a real dumbass, ya know that?
No, I mean, why—
Subaru...
A-Are you saying you can't
trust me with this?
Huh?
Because you saw me failing.
So you want to do it instead?
That's not it! But you shouldn't
have to face your past if—
But if I don't face it,
I'll never get past the trial!
If I turn my eyes away
from things I don't like,
leave them all to you, and run away...
What would be left for me then?
Let's stop talking about this.
Got a minute?
Why were you so opposed to what I suggested?
Because—
Because it is what Young Ros wants.
Young Ros believes that Emilia-sama should
be the one to liberate the Sanctuary.
And you guys back him on that?
Don't get me wrong!
I hate that son of a bitch as much as you do.
But... you get it, don't you?!
I guess...
even if the barrier disappeared and Sanctuary
officially became part of his domain...
This land is overseen by Young Ros.
No one among us wishes to defy
him and endanger our position.
I hope you and the others
know that I am sorry.
It just keeps getting harder and
harder for me to trust Roswaal.
Anyway! It's gotta be the princess
who goes through the trial!
Even if you are qualified,
I ain't lettin' you do it!
Damn it... Emilia...
No, take it easy.
I need to figure out what
to do about the mansion.
There's no way that insane woman won't
do anything to Rem and the new maids.
It's Frederica I'm worried about.
Does she have ties to Elsa somehow?
In any case, I need to get back
to the mansion as fast as I can.
And what is it you would like me to do?
Get the people of Arlam Village back home.
I want you to bring up that suggestion
to Ryuzu-san and the rest.
It doesn't look like I'll be able to
get them to agree with me this time.
"This time"?
Hmm... And why is that?
That Garfiel punk seems to hate my guts.
I don't have time to convince
someone as volatile as him.
And there's one other thing.
I want to go and tell the
people who're still in Arlam
that their families are safe.
I'm going back there alone to tell them that.
Of course, I'm also going to the mansion,
where Frederica's planning something.
Ram has informed me of this.
But given what I know about her,
Frederica would not be hasty in—
And what do you know?
Frederica gave Emilia the glowing stone.
That's proof she's planning something!
And if she does prove to be
an enemy, what will you do?
I'm sorry to say so, but you
stand no chance against her.
Emilia's dealing with
the barrier, you're injured,
and Otto won't have any part in all this.
We're stuck.
That is true, with the exception of one person.
If I may be blunt, I don't like this.
You're still talking like that, Nee-sama?
With Roswaal-sama in his current condition,
I don't like the idea of leaving his side.
Yeah, but it's not like you can
do anything for him, right?
I couldn't believe it when I heard that
Garfiel put those bandages on him.
Don't be a fool.
What if I had put them on him and
only made his injuries worse?
Show a little guilt, would you?!
Makin' your triumphant return
with a pretty girl on each arm?
You've really got some nerve, you know that?
I didn't expect you to come out so
early in the morning to see me off.
So you heard?
Frankly, it pisses me off that
this was all decided without me,
but I ain't gonna fight it.
Really? That's good to know.
If you'd tried to stop me,
I would've had to throw Ram off
into the distance as a decoy.
Like that would even work!
Would it?
How would I know?!
You should say something to...
Ram? What's wrong?
This stupid conversation gave
me a headache, that's all.
Well, I'm outta here.
I should be back tomorrow,
so look after things until then.
You're not gonna say goodbye to the princess?
I'm surprised you're actually
worried about Emilia.
But it's fine. I left her a letter.
By the way, don't you have
anything to give me?
Huh? The hell are you talkin' about?
Then are you going to show
some concern for me?
The woman you love is leaving
to fulfill her duty.
Have you no desire to offer
her some assistance?
You're only nice when you'll get
somethin' out of it, aren't ya?
There!
Take care of Emilia.
Do the best you can to let her know I'm
sorry from the bottom of my heart!
Tell her that yourself, damn it!
So, Barusu...
Will this thing Garf gave us be of some use?
I don't know.
What do you think? You've known
him longer than I have.
Actually, I have no idea.
Since it's part of a matching pair,
I'm sure it means something to him.
You've looked pretty unhappy today.
What you said earlier...
When you said you would throw me as a decoy.
For some reason, that bothered
me more than I expected.
Almost as if...
something like that has really happened before.
Barusu?
Ram, there's something important
I need to tell you.
The most important thing in the world to you.
The only thing that important
to me is Roswaal-sama.
No, there's something else.
So I'm going to tell you about it.
There's a girl named Rem...
Please don't let anything be happening.
I'm here two days earlier than last time.
If it still goes wrong,
I'll have to take off on Patrasche
the moment I wake up in the graveyard.
If Frederica turns out to be an enemy,
it's crucial to know when
she's going to take action.
Barusu?
Should I attack or run?
If it's Elsa I'm dealing with,
it'd be wise to turn tail and run.
Which means...
Barusu!
What? I was thinking about—
Welcome back, Subaru-sama.
You returned much sooner than I expected.
Is something wrong, Subaru-sama?
Oh, God! You're just so cute!
What, what?! What is this?! Subaru!
Damn! You have no idea what I've been through!
Seriously... Damn it...
Is that...
Oh... It's to match the one I gave you.
Are you hurt?
No.
I'm just incredibly relieved,
from the bottom of my heart.
It's good to be back, Petra.
If I may be blunt, I don't like this.
I feel like I've heard that before...
Yes, because it was sarcasm.
The cute sarcasm of a Ram who has
been forgotten and left at a loss.
Um, you're Ram-neesama, right?
I was just hired as a new maid in
service to the lord of the mansion.
I'm Petra.
It's a pleasure to meet you.
You seem to know your place, unlike Barusu.
Very good. I give you a passing grade.
By the way, Barusu, you fail.
I won't allow you to cross
this mansion's threshold.
What was the point of coming back, then?!
Hey, Petra... has anything weird
happened while we were away?
Like, with Frederica?
Frederica-neesama?
There's nothing weird about her at all.
Is she inside right now?
She's out patrolling the forest barrier.
It may be a while before she gets back.
I'm not sure if our timing is good or bad.
What should we do, Barusu?
I want to see what she's going to do.
We'll wait with Rem in the meantime.
I'm going to get back to cleaning.
If you need anything, please call for me.
You're nervous, huh?
I am not.
Well, you should be.
It's the right reaction. I want you to be.
I'm so glad you're all right.
Barusu...
What?
Could you leave us alone for a bit?
It's a start...
It's a start.
You returned sooner than
I expected, Subaru-sama.
What a surprise.
Since Emilia-sama is not with you,
I assume the trial is not yet complete?
Yeah.
There are some things I want to ask you.
First, about this.
That is...
Garf's stone.
Yeah. So you really do know him...
I mean, you really are related?
Garf did not tell you so himself?
It's easy enough to guess from your faces.
And I imagine you're the older sibling.
You are correct.
I am Garf's...
Garfiel's older sister by blood.
Answer me something.
Why did you use the glowing stone
to set a teleport trap?
Can't tell me that because
of your oath, either?
Well, this is one thing you need to—
Subaru-sama...
What do you mean by "teleport"?
I-I do not know how to respond to that look.
Wait! Wait, wait!
You won't fool me!
I know you're working with the conservatives
who don't want the Sanctuary to be freed!
Conservatives? I do not know what you mean.
You will need to explain everything
from the beginning...
Y-You're really not acting or signaling?
Having one-on-one time with
Frederica in my absence?
It would seem you have no
need for your life, Barusu.
Uh, no, I was...
Your skill at making tea hasn't
improved since we left, I see.
Oh... but making tea is
the one thing I excel at.
What an unlovable girl you are.
I'm perfectly lovable.
If I were more lovable,
the world would be in danger.
You always have a sharp retort ready.
Honestly...
How very like you.
And?
If you don't know about the teleporting,
why did you give Barusu the glowing stone?
Well...
You can't tell us because of your oath?
If so, that's a pathetic excuse, Frederica.
You are right.
I cannot tell you anything.
Sticking to your pathetic excuse, I see.
Then there's nothing more to discuss.
Hey, take it easy!
Your refusal to answer the question
makes your betrayal clear.
We will restrain you and
take you to the Sanctuary.
Then we can figure out who's
been giving you your orders.
Yeah, but...
If you insist on taking me to the
Sanctuary, I will not resist.
There, see? Even Frederica's—
Wait, what?
I said that I will not resist.
You... won't?
Why?!
You're awfully slow on the uptake.
Frederica can't break her
oath of her own free will,
so you'll have to use force
to make her, Barusu.
That's the kind of excuse she needs.
You guys are in perfect sync.
Naturally.
We've known each other for nearly ten years.
If that's all it's gonna take,
frankly, I'm relieved.
I want to get out of here as soon as—
Oh, dear.
I wish you wouldn't say such unfriendly things.
Now, let's keep that promise we made.
Nee-sama...
Subaru...
Run!
El Fula!
Partial beast transformation...
You have demihuman blood. How lovely.
Petra!
I'll shred you!
Her arm...
Goodness, that hurt.
I thought I was a goner.
I like it.
Maids in large, medium, and small, and one boy.
I'll put you all on a table and
compare what's inside your bellies.
Even Garf's pick-up lines are better!
Barusu!
I know!
Shamac!
We're leaving!
Subaru!
Frederica!
Ul Fula!
Frederica-neesama!
I underestimated our opponent.
Ow...
Damn it... Did we get her?
It didn't feel like it. Who was she?
Rem... Beatrice...
We have to save them.
We leave them here.
The four of us will escape
and leave them here.
That's the best option right now.
What... did you...
What the hell are you saying?!
What good will yelling do? Calm yourself.
That's Rem inside the mansion! Your sister!
You love her, and she loves you!
You have to protect your little sister!
I only made the appropriate judgment.
Losing you along with Frederica and me
would be a far greater loss for our side.
Sacrifices must be made.
You're talking about sacrificing—
Yes, she may be my younger sister.
I sensed that the same blood
flows in her as in me.
But her existence itself is a blank.
Still, if she is my sister,
this is what she would say:
"Please sacrifice me to save Roswaal-sama."
I... didn't bring you here
to make you say that.
I believe we should save the two of them.
Both Beatrice-sama and Rem
are also vital to our side.
M-Me, too! I think we should save them, too!
I agree with her!
We're not taking a majority vote.
Be quiet, child.
I-I may be a child, but I'm plenty grown-up!
Frederica-neesama even said
I'm more useful than you!
Frederica, what did you say to her?
Since it was my idea, I will assume
the task of stopping the enemy.
So you're deliberately choosing
to draw the short straw again.
You're just like Garf.
You girls are my precious junior colleagues.
Also, it is incorrect to
say I am "just like Garf."
Garf is the one who imitates me.
So this is a beast transformation?
Petra, I am sorry for frightening you.
You can still talk like that?
I am still me, after all.
You did wonderfully,
resisting the urge to scream.
Yes...
Yes! Please be careful!
Good girl.
Ram, I leave the rest in your hands.
No need to remind me.
But if you fall too far behind,
I'll make you regret it.
Snap out of it!
Let's go.
Right... We'll start with Rem.
This is bad...
This is bad. This is bad...
We've gotta hurry upstairs!
A mabeast?!
This way!
El Fula!
Why is a mabeast here?!
There's no time for questions.
It's here, and that's that!
I'll go fetch the ground dragon from the stable.
You mean Patrasche?
With a mabeast here, we'll need transportation.
Retrieve the two of them while I draw it away.
Fula!
Follow me!
Okay... Now's my—
Subaru?!
You're bleeding!
This is gonna hurt! Be strong!
Three, two...
Thanks...
But what happened to "one"?
You were less tense this way.
Petra... I'm sorry.
I'm always putting you in danger.
Don't say silly things like
that! I'm grateful to you!
You always come to save me when I'm in danger!
So this time, it's my turn.
We'll get Rem-neesama and
Beatrice-chan out of here,
and escape with Ram-neesama and
Frederica-neesama. All of us!
You're amazing, Petra. I feel so pathetic.
You're not—
No, I didn't mean that as a complaint.
I meant I've gotta try harder
to be as amazing as you.
Let's go.
Like you said, we're all gonna get out of here.
Yeah!
Oh!
Wh-What?!
I meant "Yes," not "Yeah"!
That is... The appropriate
response was "Yes"!
I'll have Frederica or Ram scold you lat—
...rusu! Barusu!
That was a mistake. I should
have come to check sooner.
I must do what I must do.
I'm going to do so, too.
That's it. Very good.
Pa...asche...
This... is...
Are you okay, Pet—
Ah, you've finally found me!
Where's... Frederica?
You mean the big maid?
Don't worry.
She proved to be quite enjoyable.
Who sent you after us?
I don't speak of my clients.
I do have that much courtesy, at least.
Though, since you came back
sooner than expected,
this didn't play out exactly
as my directions specified.
Not as... specified...
Two maids and one shut-in...
It was supposed to be timed to your return.
This is... enough.
True. I don't want Maylie taking
any more credit from me.
So let's end this now.
I'll send you to meet the angels.
Even if this world won't last,
I won't let her hurt Rem!
Rem!
Why...
Why did you save me?!
The Maiden's Gospel
Beatrice!